Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Jewish American Left TAM.511
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Jewish American Left
2007-
TAM.511
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
0.0010 linear feet (1+ websites; i.e., a collecction of websites that grows on an ongoing basis
Tamiment Library.
Scope and Content Note
Contains periodically archived websites of progressive/left Jewish American entities concerned with a range of issues, including Jewish identity and culture, anti-semitism, economic and social justice for Jews and others, the Arab-Israeli conflict (critical of the policies of Israel, especially of building settlements in the occupied territories), Jews and the labor movement, Jews and the left. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl.
Note: if a link does not work, use this URI (http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/JewishAmericanLeft), to access the archive, then use the site list to select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Jewish American Left, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left)," can be found at the website Web Archives from New York University Libraries.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arab-Israeli conflict |x Foreign public opinion, American.; Jewish radicals |z United States.; Jews |x Identity.; Jews |x Political activity |z United States.; Labor Zionism |z United States.; Socialism and Judaism.
- Jewish American Left Web Archive, 2007-
  - Ameinu, 03/15/2009-
  - American Jews for a Just Peace, 5/5/2011-
  - Bend the Arc (formerly Progressive Jewish Alliance and Jewish Funds for Justice), 6/1/2011-
  - Brit Tzedek v'Shalom - Jewish Alliance for Justice and Peace, 09/29/2007-
  - J-Street, 6/4/2011-
  - Jewish Alliance for Law and Social Action, 07/30/2009-
  - Jewish Currents Magazine, 7/27/2009-
  - Jewish Funds for Justice, 7/25/2009-
  - Jewish Peace Fellowship, 07/24/2009-
  - Jewish Voice for Peace, 07/26/2009-
  - Jews Against the Occupation, 07/26/2009-
  - Jews for Racial and Economic Justice (U.S.), 09/29/2007-
  - Jews Say No:Not in our Name!, 6/20/2011-
  - Meretz USA, 12/24/2008-
  - Mondoweiss, 11/1/2009-
  - New Jewish Agenda, 07/24/2009
  - Open Letter from American Jews, 10/13/2011-
  - Progressive Jewish Alliance, 09/29/2007-
  - Tikkun Magazine, 7/21/2011-
  - USTOGAZA, 5/6/2011-
  - Workmen's Circle/Arbeter Ring, 09/29/2007-